20多年的
Over 20 years?
30年呢
Thirty?
Forty?
-50年呢  -55年
- How about fifty? - Fifty-five.
55年
Fifty-five years.
你叫什么  女士
And what is your name, ma'am?
-艾格尼丝  -是圣徒艾格尼丝吧
- Agnes. - Yeah, I think you mean Saint Agnes.
是啊  没错
Yes. Yes, I do.
弗兰西斯和我的婚姻才到那一半的年头
Well, Francis and I are only halfway there,
但我打赌你对你丈夫就像对自己一样了解
but I bet you know your husband as well as you know yourself.
-我说得对吗  -对  是这样
- Am I right? - Yes, I do.
我了解弗兰西斯·安德伍德
Well, I know Francis Underwood.
我知道什么让他夜不能寐
I know what keeps him up at night.
我确信那原因跟你们的丈夫一样
And I'm sure it's the same thing that keeps your husbands up, too.
是未来  我要怎么给家庭带来更美好的未来
The future. How can I ensure a better future for my family?
但是  弗兰西斯  作为总统...
Except... Francis, as President...
他的关注着全美国的家庭
his focus is on the progress of all American families.
你们知道他昨晚跟我说什么吗
You know what he said to me last night?
他说"克莱尔  我整个总统工作目标很简单
He said, "Claire, my entire presidential agenda, it's very simple.
我想看着每一个美国人的眼睛
I want to be able to look every single American in the eye,
知道自己让他们过得更好了"
and know that I have made their lives better."
请讲
Yes.
我得说  安德伍德夫人
I have to say, Mrs. Underwood,
我觉得您很有魅力
I find you very charming.
看起来也很诚实
And you seem quite honest.
但我无法相信
But I have trouble believing
您丈夫真的关心人民
that your husband truly cares about people.
弗兰西斯·安德伍德是个好人
Well, Francis Underwood is a good man.
他甘于奉献  慷慨大方
He's dedicated and generous.
我有28年的亲身经历为证
And I have 28 years of proof.
而且我可以说  即使我没嫁给他
And I can honestly say, even if I wasn't married to him,
也会投票给他
he would definitely have my vote.
谢谢你
Thank you.
渎职  任人唯亲
Negligence. Nepotism.
侵吞联邦基金
Misappropriation of federal funds.
外交政策失败  还有隐瞒事实
A foreign policy fiasco and loose with the truth.
这五根指头共同指向哪里
What do these five fingers have in common?
弗兰西斯·J·安德伍德
Francis J. Underwood.
邓巴
金先生  我想回应一下
Mr. King, I would like to respond to that.
此人藐视法律
This is a man who believes in the rule of law-ish.
不顾立法程序  罔顾宪法
The legislative process-ish. The Constitution-ish.
这样的人应该当总统吗
Is this the man who should be president?
邓巴女士  你像个好律师那样
Ms. Dunbar, like any good lawyer,
有绝佳的辞令
you have a knack for rhetoric-ish.
但美国人民听够空话了
But the American people are tired of words.
他们渴望的是实际行动
What they crave is action.
我担心我强调"行动"这个词
My concern about focusing on the word, "action,"
她会用失败的行动回击
is that she'll just come back with failed actions.
《美国就业法案》  联合国维和任务
America Works, the UN mission.
"行动"在上轮民调的关键人群中反响不错
"Action" performed well with key demos in our last poll.
是  但这不会偏离主题吗
Yes, but doesn't this take us off message?
我们一直说  "支持弗兰克·安德伍德
We have been saying, "A vote for Frank Underwood
就是支持《美国就业法案》"
is a vote for America Works."
我们一直在宣传那个
That's what we've been running on.
你得找一个比《美国就业法案》更广的词
You need a word that goes beyond America Works.
任何情况都能用的
Something that can be used for anything.
雷米  你怎么看
Remy, what do you think?
我们在讨论"行动"这个词
We're talking about the word, "action."
抱歉  我刚刚...
Sorry, I was, uh...
我在想外交政策的论点
my mind was on the foreign policy argument.
-我想提前考虑好  -"愿景"怎么样
- I was just thinking ahead. - What about "vision"?
不会太泛泛了吗
Isn't that too generic?
就是这目的啊  越概括越好
That's what we want. I mean, the more generic, the better.
人们可以把任何事投射到"愿景"上
People can project anything they want on "vision."
我明天之前做好民调
I'll get it polled before tomorrow.
下面该准备与夏普的辩论了
We should work on Sharp next.
要我扮她吗
You want me to play her?
谢谢你这么认真地扮演  唐纳德
Thank you for taking your role so seriously, Donald.
你应该考虑当演员
You should consider a career on the stage.
因为他是别想跟我竞选了
Because he sure as hell isn't gonna be on my ticket.
你做这个很厉害  她们都喜欢你
You're good at this. They loved you.
竞选三十年  就知道怎么观察听众了
Three decades of campaigns, you learn how to read an audience.
我受不了自我推销
Self-promotion gives me hives.
真不知道你怎么做到的
Honestly, I don't know how you do it.
我是在推销我丈夫  不是我自己
I'm promoting my husband, not myself.
这借口真方便啊
That's a convenient way to spin it, don't you think?
你说话一向这么直白吗
Are you always this blunt?
我只能再随行两天了
I only have two days to tag along.
介意我跟你一车吗  我们时间挺紧的
Mind if I ride with you, since we have so little time?
我得打几个电话  也许以后吧
I need to make some calls. Maybe we'll find some time later.
雷米  你之前走神了  怎么回事
Remy, you were distracted earlier. What's going on?
没什么  一切都好
Nothing. Everything's good.
我需要你拿出最佳表现  雷米
I need you on your A-game, Remy.
这场辩论可能让我们领先
This debate could make us the front-runner.
只是又要竞选  又要管理白宫
It's just between the campaign and managing the White House,
我有点精疲力尽了
I'm a little burnt out.
我们还有好几个月要忙  普选前还有一年
We still have months to go. A year before the general.
只是暂时的  我会好起来
It's temporary. I'll get past it.
你能做到  我也能
If you can do it, I can.
未知号码来电
嘉文
Gavin?
-你好  道格拉斯  -你想怎么样
- Hello, Douglas. - What do you want?
你还是不肯相信她死了  对吗
You still can't believe she's dead, can you?
你不该信  因为她没死
Well, you shouldn't. 'Cause she's not.
她还活着  我知道她的确切住址
She's alive, and I know exactly where she is.
我早就知道了
I've known for a while.
-什么  -看你的电脑
- What? - Look on your laptop.
不可能  你给我看过照片
No, you... you showed me the picture.
-她尸体的照片  -那不是她
- Of her body. - That wasn't her.
全是我伪造的  好让你给我的护照解锁
I forged it all so you'd lift my passport lock.
我已经逃出来了  道格
Well, I'm out now, Doug.
我很安全  但我朋友仍有危险
And I'm safe. But my friend isn't.
去找格林
Talk to Green.
给他拿到跟我一样的协议  撤销所有起诉
Get him the same deal you got me, all charges dropped.
你照做  我就告诉你她在哪
You do that, and I'll tell you where she is.
翻译   面条打包子
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   香茗小焙
翻译   吃货丁小七
翻译   西西
翻译   艾瑞卡
翻译   肉松富士
时间轴   萌
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
特效   草草
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第十一集
-密查姆  -先生
- Hey, Meechum. - Sir.
总统先生
Mr. President.
感谢你赶来安德鲁空军基地
Thank you for coming all the way to Andrews.
雷米跟你说过总体方案了吗
Did Remy walk you through the broad strokes?
不论是国际还是国内的政策问题
No matter the policy question, foreign or domestic,
我们都抨击邓巴经验不足
we hammer Dunbar's lack of experience.
要猛烈攻击
We bludgeon it.
尽可能地强调"经验不足"
We cannot say "lack of experience" enough.
毫无疑问  她会提起克莱尔休会任命一事
And no doubt, she'll bring up Claire's recess appointment,
我不能发表看法  所以这个话题就交给你
where I can't take the bait, so I leave that entirely to you.
这正是我想跟你讨论的问题之一
This was one of the things that I was hoping to discuss.
你不想说她性别歧视吗
Oh, you don't want to call her "sexist"?
-这论点站不住脚  -能站住脚
- The argument doesn't hold. - It does hold.
她说克莱尔不胜任那份工作
She says that Claire was unqualified.
你说换了有同样履历的男人她就不会那么说
You say she wouldn't say that about a man with the same CV.
我觉得这未必
I'm not sure that's true.
而且指责另一位女性性别歧视
And calling another woman sexist
特别是台上还有一位男性
when there's a man on the stage--
没有比你更合适的人选
And who else is better but you
指责她在女性问题上
to call her out on what she's done for women,
根本无所作为
which is absolutely nothing?
而通过立法促进性别平等是你的标志之一
Whereas gender-equality legislation is one of your hallmarks.
但这对我的伤害可能远大于对她
But it could hurt me more than it hurts her.
我以为我们已达成共识
I thought we had an understanding.
你咄咄逼人  我保持气度
You were gonna play pit bull while I play presidential.
你会惹火上身吗  对  有可能
Will you get a little bloody? Yes, probably.
但这不就是辩论的目的吗
But that's what people want in their debates.
然后你与我携手  我们一起埋了她
And then you and I together, we bury her.
再下个星期你退选  转而支持我
You drop out next week, endorse me
竞选就此结束
and the race is over.
我不介意当打手
I have no problem being forceful.
但这个性别歧视  还有择校的问题
But this sexism thing, and the whole school argument, I--
你是说她的孩子
You mean her kids.
我真的不想把他们扯进来
I really don't want to involve them.
有两点我们希望美国人民知道
We have two things we want the American people to hear:
她经验不足
she lacks experience
还有她含着金钥匙出生
and she was born with a silver spoon in her mouth.
但肯定还有别的办法
But there has to be another way.
她想鼓吹同一起跑线
She wants to trumpet an equal playing field?
那她为什么还送自己的孩子上私立学校
Then why does she send her own kids to private school?
这是一个简单清晰的观点
That is a clear and simple argument
所有人都能明白
that everyone can get their heads around.
而且加分的是
And it doesn't hurt
爱荷华州最大的雇佣单位就是公立学校系统
that Iowa's biggest employer is the public school system.
艾伦也送他的孩子上私立学校
Alan sends his kids to private school.
对  但他们不是你的孩子
Yeah, but they're not your kids.
我是他们的继母  我会被批为伪君子
They're my step-kids. And that makes me a hypocrite.
这才是你真正在意的吗
Is that really what you're concerned about?
被称为伪君子
Being a hypocrite?
这事关我的家人
It's my family.
相信我  等他们走进白宫
Oh, trust me, they'll understand
就会理解你的
the moment they step into the White House.
杰姬  真不该用我来说服你
Jackie, I really shouldn't have to convince you
为住进那里无所不用其极
to do what it takes to get a set of keys.
我会咄咄逼人的  总统先生
I'll be the pit bull, Mr. President.
谢谢你  杰姬
Thank you, Jackie.
-可以了吗  -媒体已经登机  先生
- Are we all clear? - The press has boarded, sir.
-好  确保没人看到她  -是  先生
- All right, make sure no one sees her. - Yes, sir.
今天飞往得梅因将用时两小时
Flight time to Des Moines today will be two hours...
真是可惜  她的坚决务实
Such a pity how much ruthless pragmatism
被家庭价值观拖了后腿
gets weighed down by family values.
要是没有她那位医生和满脸粉刺的孩子
Without her doctor and his pimply-faced brood,
她本可一飞冲天
she could soar as high as this plane.
我知道让她结婚是我的主意  不用你提醒
Oh, I know, the marriage was my idea. Don't remind me.
道格
Doug.
-你没事吧  -我没事
- You okay? - Yeah. I'm all right.
怎么了  被锁在门外了吗
What, did you get locked out or something?
我之前想喝酒
I felt the need to drink.
我走到这儿  然后阻止了自己
I got this far and I stopped myself.
好吧
Okay.
我想让你看到
I wanted you to see it.
我可以控制自己
That I could control it.
你想回去吗
You wanna go back up?
好
Yeah.
我知道这看起来很过激
I know it looks crazy.
但我必须那么做
But I had to do it.
为什么
Why?
有个女孩  我受伤之前认识的
There was this girl... before the injury.
她离开了我  然后我开始酗酒
She left me. So I started drinking.
我试过忘记她
I tried to shut her out,
但我还是忍不住去查邮件和短信
but I just kept checking my e-mails, my text messages.
不能再那样下去了
It needed to stop.
她是谁
Who was she?
算了  没关系
You know what? That's okay.
无所谓了
Doesn't matter.
重要的是  你今天被推到悬崖边
What matters is that you got pushed to the edge today
却没掉下去
and you didn't fall off.
你做了你该做的
You did what you had to do.
我不因此指责你
I don't judge you for it.
我也不觉得这过激
And I don't think it's crazy.
我们本可以在暖和点的地方见面
We could've met somewhere a little warmer.
沃尔玛想把这片拆光  建起超市
Walmart wanted to knock this down, build a store here.
-但是被社区阻止了  -我知道
- But the community put a stop to it. - I know.
因为他们不答应税收抵免
Because they wouldn't give a tax credit
除非最低工资标准提高
unless entry-level wages were higher.
一份糟透了的工作和没有工作  哪个更好
So which is better? A shitty job, or no job?
-我想我知道你的答案  -别那么肯定
- Well, I think I know your answer. - Don't be so sure.
杰姬  你一再反对
Jackie, you have repeatedly
我想让领导层推行的
opposed the minimum-wage and CEO salary bill
《最低工资和高管薪酬标准法案》
I asked the leadership to introduce.
我考虑了很多
I've put a lot of thought into it.
这个社区表明了它的立场
This community took a stand.
如果足够多的人站出来  国会只能行动
If enough of them do, Congress won't have a choice but to act.
我们是为了讨论立法而来的吗
Are we here to talk about legislation?
因为我们六个小时后就都要参加辩论了
Because we both have a debate in six hours.
我想支持你
I want to endorse you.
今晚我不攻击你  我们一起攻击安德伍德
I'll lay off you tonight. You and I attack Underwood.
三天后  我退出并支持你
In three days, I'll drop out and endorse.
第一次党团会议还没开过呢
We haven't even had the first caucus.
你们俩势均力敌
You two are neck-and-neck.
我在爱荷华有14%  新罕布什尔是12%
I have 14 points in Iowa, twelve in New Hampshire.
你得到我选民的支持  就能在两个州稳赢
You get my people, you have a clear win in both states.
我的支持是很宝贵的
My endorsement is valuable.
那安德伍德有多看重呢
How much does Underwood value it?
-非常看重  -他开出什么条件
- Highly. - What did he offer you?
我更想知道你能开出什么价码
I'm more interested in what you have to offer.
他保证给你内阁席位
Did he promise a cabinet position?
还不止吗
More than that?
他要带你一起竞选  是吗
He offered to put you on the ticket, didn't he?
我不指望你会带我竞选  希瑟
I wouldn't expect to be on your ticket, Heather.
你需要个带把儿的南方人
You need a Southerner with a penis.
考虑到我的战争经验  我想要国防部长
I was thinking Secretary of Defense, given my war record.
但其他的我也愿考虑
But I'd be open to other ideas.
有你支持当然好  杰姬  但我不能给你什么
I would love your support, Jackie, but I offer you nothing.
但是...这能轻巧取胜
But... this is an easy win.
我不会还没入主白宫
I'm not gonna start selling off cabinet positions
就出售内阁席位
before I've won the White House.
这种决定应该完全按资质做出
Those decisions will be based purely on merit.
我要是帮你拿下了提名
If I'm gonna lock up this nomination for you,
就理应得到报酬
I deserve to be compensated.
我想获胜  杰姬  只是方法与你不同
I plan on winning, Jackie. Just... not your way.
不管你支不支持我
And with or without your support.
那我可就跟安德伍德一条心了
Then I'm sticking with Underwood.
你做你该做的吧
You do what you have to do.
杰姬在吗
Is Jackie in here?
鲍勃
Hi, Bob.
不好意思我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
-手术进行得如何  -糟透了
- How did your surgery go? - Terrible.
病人差点没挺过去
The patient almost didn't make it.
但是他还活着
But he's alive?
是她  还活着  情况稳定了
She. And yeah. Stable condition.
你能来对我意义重大
It means so much to me that you came.
妆化好了
All done.
-还满意吗  -很不错  谢谢
- Do you like? - It's good. Thank you.
-那什么怎么样了  -谢谢
- So, how'd it go with--? - Thanks.
她开出什么条件
What'd she offer?
什么都没有
Nothing.
-完全没有吗  -是啊  我也没想到
- Nothing at all? - I know, I was surprised, too.
太不明智了  她本可锁定胜局
It's foolish. She could lock this up.
但不得不承认  我几乎心生敬意
I have to say, I almost... respect it.
不管怎样  你是对的
Anyway, you were right.
忠于你了解的那个魔鬼
Stick with the devil you know.
孩子们今晚会看辩论吗
Are the kids watching tonight?
会的  他们把朋友都叫到家里了
Yeah. They've got all their friends over at the house.
那个  孩子...
Listen, the ki--
怎么了
What?
没什么  我看起来怎么样
Nothing. How do I look?
我想立马把你扔到床上
I'd throw you on that bed right now
可惜会弄乱你的头发
if it wouldn't mess up your hair.
看我准备吧
Watch me prep.
辩论结束之后你想怎么弄乱我头发都随你
You can mess up my hair all you want after the debate.
-她来了  -她来了
- She's here. - There she is.
安静  安静  她来了
Quiet, guys. Quiet, guys. Here she comes.
安静
Quiet, quiet!
谢谢  感谢你们  大家好
Thank you. Thank you. Hello, everyone!
非常感谢大家
Thank all of you so very much
为我们能拿下新罕布什尔这么努力
for working so hard to make sure we take New Hampshire.
正是这样的办事处能让我们赢得初选
It is field offices like this that win primaries,
总统想让大家知道
and the president wants you to know
你们的奉献对我们来说多么重要
how much your dedication means to us.
真的感谢大家  谢谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
谁想看辩论
Now, who's ready to watch a debate?
在苏城  人们齐聚一堂
There is a large crowd here in Sioux City tonight.
爱荷华州民主党竞选辩论
我想说潜在选民  但当然在爱荷华
I would say potential voters, but of course, here in Iowa,
市民们是通过党团会议而非投票的方式初选
citizens caucus instead of vote,
而今天到场的许多人
and many of the people here in this room
都会参加1月15日的党团会议
will be doing just that on January 15th.
一份CNN民意调查显示
A CNN ORC poll has it
目前两名领跑者的支持率不相上下
as a tight race between the two front-runners.
希瑟·邓巴的支持率为32%
Heather Dunbar at 32 percent.
弗兰克·安德伍德总统的支持率为30%
President Frank Underwood at 30 percent.
杰姬·夏普议员女士以14%排在第三位
Congresswoman Jackie Sharp trails in third at 14 percent.
还有22%尚未决定
Twenty-two percent remain undecided.
你可以换台
You can switch it.
真的吗
Really?
除非你想看
Unless you want to watch.
不  我以为你想看
No, I thought you would.
这是你在这里的最后一晚
It's your last night here.
我想和我哥哥一起度过
I want to spend it with my brother,
而不是弗兰克·安德伍德
not Frank Underwood.
那你想看什么
What do you want to watch instead?
随便  你想看的就行
Anything. Whatever you want.
...保证全民就业
...promising universal employment,
而在巴以关系上...
and on Israeli Palestinian relations...
天  你看过《传染病》吗
Oh, shit. Have you ever seen Contagion?
没有
No.
如果你有洁癖
If you're a clean freak,
这片子绝对能让你更加洁癖
this'll definitely make you a germ freak.
-我爱死这部电影了  -那就看吧
- I love this movie. - Go for it.
欢迎收看CNN举办的
Welcome to the first
第一场民主党提名辩论会
Democratic nomination debate hosted by CNN.
今晚的候选人为  弗兰克·安德伍德
Our candidates tonight: Frank Underwood,
杰姬·夏普和希瑟·邓巴
Jackie Sharp, and Heather Dunbar.
我是约翰·金  今晚你们的调解人
I'm John King and I'll be your moderator tonight.
辩论分为两个部分
Our debate will be divided in two parts,
第一部分聚焦外交政策
the first part focusing on foreign policy,
第二部分则着重于国内政策
part two focusing on the domestic agenda.
辩论形式如下
And our format will be as follows:
我会向每位候选人提一个问题
I will ask one candidate a question.
候选人有一分钟时间来回答
That candidate will have one minute to answer.
随后  所有候选人可以进行五分钟的
After that, all of our candidates can engage in an open conversation
自由讨论
lasting for five minutes.
首先请各位候选人进行开场陈述
We begin, though, with opening statements.
经抽签决定
And by lottery, it was decided
先从安德伍德总统开始
that President Underwood goes first.
-总统先生  -谢谢  晚上好  约翰
- Mr. President. - Thank you. And good evening, John,
另外两位候选人晚上好
good evening to my fellow candidates,
苏城的好市民们晚上好
and to the good people of Sioux City.
这次提名归根结底就是一个词  愿景
This nomination comes down to one word: vision.
我相信我已经通过《美国就业法案》向全国人民
I believe that I have shown a clear vision to this country
展现了一个清晰的愿景
with America Works,
它是近一个世纪以来最全面的就业计划
the most comprehensive jobs program in nearly a century.
我们已经证明该法案在华盛顿取得了成功
We showed it could work in Washington DC.
现在我们需要将我们的成功推广到全国
We need now to take what we did there and spread it nationwide,
这样美国梦就能真正美梦成真
so that the American dream can become the American reality.
但是光有愿景还不够
But that vision isn't enough on its own.
你们需要一个有经验的人来实现这份愿景
You need someone with experience to make it happen.
考虑到我在国会和白宫的经历
And between my time in Congress and now at the White House,
我的经验比两位对手加起来还要丰富
I have more experience than both of my opponents combined.
当你考虑雇佣一个人的时候
And, uh, when you hire someone for a job,
你是会选择有三十年工作经验的人
are you gonna hire someone with 30 years' experience,
还是不到十年工作经验的人
or someone with less than ten
还是完全没有经验的人
or someone with no experience at all?
在我南方老家那边
Where I come from down south,
我们管这种情况叫做显而易见
we call that as clear as a glass of moonshine.
接下来有请前副检察长邓巴女士
Former Solicitor General Dunbar is next.
-致开场陈述  -谢谢  约翰
- Your opening statement, please. - Thank you, John.
也感谢爱荷华人民
And thank you Iowa.
我同意总统刚才所说的
Well, I agree with the President.
愿景和经验正是美国人民需要的
Vision and experience are exactly what America needs.
不幸的是
Unfortunately,
他拥有的是错误的愿景和糟糕的经验
he has the wrong vision and horrendous experience.
你可以说《美国就业法案》有远见  但实际上
You can call America Works visionary, but in truth,
它只是一个存在了数十年的
it is just an ultra-conservative agenda
极其保守的议程
that's been around for decades.
瓦解安全保障  让人们自生自灭
Dismantle the safety net and hang people out to dry.
至于总统先生的经验
As for the President's experience,
他在领导层在任期间
he was in the leadership during
正值国会历史上最低效的时期之一
one of the most ineffective decades in Congressional history.
作为总统  他经手的每一件事都失败了
As president, he has failed at everything he's done.
《美国就业法案》在包括我在内的
America Works was illegal in the minds
许多法律专业人士看来都是违法的
of many legal experts, myself included.
他的约旦河谷计划彻底失败
His Jordan Valley plan was a disaster.
如果你把这些称为经验
If that's what you call experience,
那你不仅是在美化履历  而是伪造履历了
you're not just padding the résumé, you are fabricating it.
安德伍德总统并不是在向我们展示愿景
President Underwood isn't presenting us with a vision,
而是在说服自己相信自己的妄想
he is convincing himself of his own delusion.
我的愿景则是遏制大企业的贪婪
Now, my vision is to tackle corporate greed,
为最需要的人们提高薪酬
raise pay for those who need it most,
通过刺激经济增长制造就业
and create jobs by growing the economy,
而不是抢劫人民的退休金和医保
not robbing people of their retirement and health care.
我的经验是二十年捍卫宪法的经历
My experience is 20 years defending the Constitution.
所以你们可以肯定  当我宣誓就职时
You know when I take my presidential oath,
我会遵守誓言的每一个字
I will mean every word of it.
邓巴女士  谢谢  夏普众议员女士
Ms. Dunbar, thank you. Congresswoman Sharp,
-你的开场陈述  -谢谢
- your opening statement, please. - Thank you.
很多人都知道我曾是一名美国军人
As many of you know, I am a US Army veteran.
我曾亲睹我的战友们
Now, I've seen firsthand the great sacrifices
为守卫这个国家做出的伟大牺牲
my fellow servicemen and women have made defending this country.
但我怎能让他们去保卫这个
But how can we ask them to protect a system
没在保护我们的系统
that isn't protecting us?
比如说女性
Take women, for example.
这儿有两名女性参与了总统竞选
There are two women at this debate running for president.
十分了不起  可是在普通工作场合呢
That's extraordinary. But out in the general workforce?
男性赚一美元而女性只能赚77美分
Women earn 77 cents on the dollar compared to men.
少数裔女性甚至只有67美分
Even worse is minority women earning 67 cents on the dollar.
邓巴女士可以高谈阔论缩小贫富差距
Now, Ms. Dunbar can talk about balancing the scales,
但她继承了亿万家产
but she inherited a multi-billion-dollar fortune
从未需要去努力赚一分钱
and never had to earn any cents on the dollar.
我不认同安德伍德总统
Now, I don't agree with everything
所做或是提议的所有事
that President Underwood has done or proposes,
但至少他知道为生活辛苦打拼的滋味
but at least he knows what it means to work for a living.
我还能带给你们更多
I can give you even better than that.
我知道为生活斗争的滋味
I know what it means to fight for a living.
我将在国内努力为公平而战
And I will fight for fairness here at home
正如我当初在海外与敌人拼死斗争
just as fiercely as I fought our enemies overseas.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢  议员女士
Thank you, Congresswoman.
我们开始第一部分  对外政策
Let's move to part one: foreign policy.
第一个问题是给您的  总统先生
And the first question is for you, Mr. President.
鉴于近期约旦河谷多变的形势
Given the recent volatile events in the Jordan Valley,
您仍然认为集结
do you still believe it was correct
联合国多国军队进行干预  是正确的决定吗
to assemble the United Nations coalition and to intervene,
或者我们该承认此次行动是错误的
or is it time now to call that intervention a mistake?
我会回答这个问题的  约翰
Well, I will answer that question, John,
但我首先需要反驳
but I'd like to address first
邓巴女士刚刚说的一些话
something Ms. Dunbar said a few moments ago.
《美国就业法案》不是陈旧保守的议程
America Works is not some stale, old, conservative agenda.
你能说出一个共和党人
You name me one Republican
曾建议我们拿联邦基金
who has suggested using federal funds
为每一个想要工作的美国人
to guarantee jobs for every American
提供工作  我就把帽子吃了
who wants one and I will eat my hat.
这不是在瓦解政府  这是在...
This isn't about dismantling government. It is about--
我们不是该讨论对外政策吗
Aren't we supposed to be talking about foreign policy?
我会谈到的  但首先
Yeah, I will. But first,
-我想纠正一下...  -因为谈论
- I'd like to correct... - because it's easier to talk about
《美国就业法案》
America Works
比维护你站不住脚的联合国行动更容易
than to defend your indefensible UN mission.
至少我有可维护的过去  邓巴女士
At least I have a record to defend, Ms. Dunbar.
说到过去  总统先生
Speaking of your record, Mr. President,
您曾公开表明不会竞选总统
you went on record saying you wouldn't run for president.
-可却还是参选了  -约翰  看起来
- And yet here you are. - John, it seems that
你精心制定的规则已经失效了
your very thoughtful rules have gone out the window.
您对规则毫不尊重  总统先生
You have no respect for rules, Mr. President.
比如联邦应急管理署
Take FEMA, for example.
你现在要说联邦应急管理署
Oh, you want to talk about FEMA now
而非对外政策了吗
instead of foreign policy.
我只是顺着您的话往下接
I am just following your lead, sir.
看我们在您的领导下
See what a mess we get into
陷入怎样的混乱啊
when we follow your brand of leadership?
我必须承认  邓巴女士
Well, I must admit that Ms. Dunbar
确实在辞令华丽的辩论方面
does have many years of experience
有多年经验
making rhetorical arguments in court.
今天看到的就是最好的证明
You've just seen proof of that today.
可是服务美国人民并非靠口头上的功夫
But serving the American people is not about what you say,
而在于行动
it's about what you do.
我想问  你做了什么
And I would ask: what have you ever done?
我同意  邓巴女士经验的缺乏令人担心
I have to agree that Ms. Dunbar's lack of experience is a concern.
总统居然提起经验的重要性
I find it ironic that the president talks about
讽刺的是
the importance of experience,
他任命了毫无任何资质的妻子
given the fact that he appointed his wife UN ambassador
为联合国大使
despite her utter lack of credentials.
这是性别歧视
That's a sexist comment.
你说什么
Excuse me?
如果是一名女性总统任命自己的丈夫
You wouldn't be making that argument
你肯定不会这么说
if a female president had appointed her husband.
一个像克莱尔·安德伍德那样缺乏
A husband with the same lack of international affairs experience
外交经验的丈夫吗  我还是会的
as Claire Underwood? Yes, I would.
事实上  这让我质疑你对于女性的支持
In fact, it makes me question your advocacy for women in general.
真荒谬
Well, that's ridiculous.
你在推动性别平等方面做过什么
What have you done to further gender equality?
你在缩小贫富差距方面做过什么
What have you done to balance the scales?
那是你的口号
That's your slogan, and yet
可你却无视了一半的人口
you've left half of the population out of the mix.
事实不是这样的
But that is simply not true.
你能说出一件事吗
Can, can you name one specific thing?
当然  我是史上少有的
Yes, I can. Being a woman, who has served as Solicitor General,
曾担任过副检察长的女性
one of the few in the history of the court.
这符合你个人的利益
Well, that advanced your interests,
可那对于1.5亿女性有什么用呢
but what did that do for 150 million women out there?
身为女性能够担任这样的职位
The very fact that a woman can hold that position--
-那么你是一种象征  -某种程度上我是
- So you are a symbol. - In a way, yes, I suppose I am.
包括你在内的很多女性
Me and many other women, including yourself--
可这样能够让我们
Okay, but how does that get us
从挣77美分变成一美元吗
from 77 cents on the dollar to 100?
真实的钱  不是象征意义的
Real cents. Not symbolic cents.
你现在只是在模仿总统的说辞
Well, now you're just aping the president's rhetoric.
又是性别歧视
Another sexist comment.
-你怎么可以这么扭曲我的话  -我只代表自己
- How could you possibly misconstrue my words? - I speak for myself.
我不是在模仿总统  或者任何男人
I am not aping the president or any other man.
抱歉  我不会回应这种...
I'm sorry, I won't engage with this--
战场上  战事激烈的时候
You know, when things get tough on the battlefield,
我们可不会说
we never say,
"抱歉  我不会回应[开火]"
"Sorry, I won't engage."
我们做出回应  邓巴女士
We engage, Ms. Dunbar.
而你得面对这个事实
And you need to confront the fact
那就是你并未把女性的利益放在心上
that you do not have women's best interests at heart.
约翰  这样没法收场了
John, this is getting out of hand.
好吧  开始下一个问题
All right, then let's move on to the next question.
现在的辩论主题是外交政策
We are in the foreign policy portion of this debate.
邓巴女士  请允许我问你这个问题
Ms. Dunbar, let me bring this question to you.
你不赞成总统的做法
You're critical of the president.
你说他在约旦河谷的所作所为完全站不住脚
You say it's indefensible, what he has done in the Jordan Valley.
-对  -如果换做是你  你具体会怎么做呢
- That's right. - But specifically, what would you do differently?
约翰  我很高兴你问了这个问题
Well, John, I'm glad you asked that.
在我看来  把军队派往
Sending troops into the
-约旦河谷算不上外交  -我得回酒店了
- Jordan Valley isn't what I call diplomacy. - I need to go back to the hotel.
各位  安德伍德夫人得走了
Everybody, Mrs. Underwood needs to leave us now.
真希望我可以留下来
I really wish I could stay,
但我明天的行程很满
but I have a very full day tomorrow.
我得回去休息了  不过我想再次感谢所有人
I should rest up. But again, I want to thank you all
感谢你们的招待还有你们的辛勤工作
for your hospitality and all of your hard work.
非常感谢各位
Thank you so much.
大家晚安
Good night, everyone.
他的滴入式外交政策只不过是又一个妄想
His trickle-down diplomacy is another example of delusion.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood.
你该回去  跟志愿者待在一起
Oh, you should go back inside with the volunteers
体验竞选的每个方面
and have the full campaign experience.
我来新罕布什尔不是为了这个
I didn't come to New Hampshire for that.
我是来找你谈话的
I came to speak with you.
也许明天吧  我现在不太清醒
Tomorrow, maybe. My brain is a bit fried.
是因为夏普的话吗
Is it what Sharp said?
你是为这个看不下去了吗
Why you don't want to watch anymore?
-那个性别歧视的发言  -我不关心那个
- The sexist comment? - Oh, I honestly don't care.
那不过是一场表演
It's all spectacle.
看谁能拉到更多支持率  不是吗
Who can get the most points, right?
晚安
Good night.
现在进行辩论的第二部分  国内政策
Now for part two of our debate: the domestic agenda.
第一个问题是给你的  议员女士
And the first question goes to you, Congresswoman.
总统提到了《美国就业法案》
The President speaks of America Works.
邓巴女士想要提高最低工资
Ms. Dunbar wants to raise minimum wage.
她提到了控制高管薪酬
Talks about regulating executive pay.
但很多人还不清楚
But a lot of people aren't quite clear
你主张的经济政策
about your economic policy.
具体来说  我特别强调"具体"
What specifically, I underscore "Specifically,"
你若当选总统会怎么做
would you do if elected president?
我要做的有很多  这点我们之前已经谈过
Well, I plan to do a lot. And we talked about this earlier.
首先  最重要的是
First and foremost,
我想推动男女平等
I want to press for gender equality
消除薪资差距
and close the salary gap.
如果一半的就业人员
If half of the working population
能拿到更多的工资
has more money in their pockets,
这会刺激消费  促进经济增长
that will catalyze spending, which will grow the economy,
最终创造更多就业机会
which will, in turn, create more jobs.
总统先生  你怎么看
Mr. President, what do you think of that?
我同意这种想法  我认为男女平等非常重要
Oh, I agree. I think that gender equality is very important.
在我主张的《美就法》中
And under my AmWorks program,
会有一项条款  《美就法》下所有的就业岗位
there will be a provision that all AmWorks jobs,
都不能出现男女薪资不平等的情况
there can be no discrepancy in pay between men and women.
《美就法》  这只是政府提供的工作
AmWorks jobs, so that's the government.
那其它的私人企业呢
What about the rest of the private sector?
我认为得先有榜样
Well, I think we have to start by leading by example,
再着手立法...
then we introduce legislation...
榜样
Leading by example?
如果《美国就业法案》就是你所谓的榜样
If America Works is how you lead by example...
抱歉  请让我说完  邓巴女士
I'm sorry, please let me finish my point, Mr. Dunbar.
如果这就是你所谓的榜样
If that is how you lead by example,
那我们是否要认为  每个人都要非法地
then are we to assume that everyone should illegally
占用他们不该占用的资金
raid funds that they have no right to use?
每个人都要去抢银行吗
Everyone should start robbing banks?
去打劫酒水店吗
Holding up liquor stores?
邓巴女士  无意冒犯
Now, Ms. Dunbar, with all due respect,
你可以尽情地批判我的计划
you can criticize my programs as much as you want,
但要指控我违法...
but to accuse me of illegal activity--
有一件事你无法否认  那就是在宪法上
One thing you can't deny is that I am much more of an authority
我懂的比你多得多  总统先生
on the Constitution than you are, Mr. President.
邓巴女士  我们三个人
Ms. Dunbar, all three of us on this stage
都曾进行过宣誓就职
have taken oaths of office.
我认为我们都捍卫了宪法
I would have to say that we have all defended the Constitution.
宪法不是你一个人的
You don't have some special claim on the Constitution.
宪法属于在座的所有人
The Constitution belongs to everyone in this room
它属于美国的每一位公民
and every citizen in the United States.
但我想问夏普女士
But I would ask Ms. Sharp,
你投票同意废除《美国就业法案》
you voted in favor of dismantling America Works.
这么做是因为你认为该法案
Was that because you thought it was in fact,
如邓巴女士所言  是非法的吗
as Ms. Dunbar says, illegal?
我当时投票废除法案  是因为我想确保
I voted for dismantlement because I wanted to make sure
我们做好了飓风的应对工作
we were prepared for the hurricane,
而不是由于我认为
not because I thought your
你对《斯塔福法案》的解读是非法的
reading of the Stafford Act was illegal per se.
真的吗  你认为总统有权做那种事吗
Honestly, you think the president had a right to do what he did?
这是拨款问题  不是法律问题
It's an appropriations issue, not a legal one.
那他的人格呢
What about his character?
他相当于直接走进联邦应急管理署对大家说
He basically walked into FEMA and said,
"举起手来  告诉我保险库在哪里"
"Stick 'em up and show me where the vault is."
我现在又成抢劫犯了  六抢·安德伍德
So now I'm a bank robber. Six Gun Underwood,
南卡罗莱纳就这么叫我
what they call me in South Carolina.
抱歉  但我不觉得这有什么好笑的
I'm sorry, but I do not find this funny.
要我说你就是伪君子
I say you are a hypocrite.
你声称在乎那些一千万失业人口
You claim to care about the ten million people out of work,
但你却盗用了他们的赈灾基金
but you will steal their Disaster Relief Fund...
这是拨款问题  邓巴女士
This is an appropriations issue, Miss Dunbar.
-社会保险和医疗福利  -我来说说什么虚伪
- Social Security and health care. - I'd like to talk about hypocrisy.
我们在华盛顿特区创造了五万个工作岗位
We put 50,000 people to work in Washington DC.
希瑟·邓巴想要缩小贫富差距
Heather Dunbar wants to balance the scales
修复失衡的系统
to fix a broken system.
与此同时她却送自己的孩子上私立学校
And yet she sends her own kids to private school.
用的并非她工作所得收入  而是继承的遗产
With money she never earned, but which she inherited.
出身显赫  却高谈贫困问题
Now, it is easy to talk about the problems of the poor
是站着说话不腰疼
with a silver spoon in your mouth.
我是否家境富裕  确实如此
Am I well-off? Absolutely.
罗斯福推行新政时也是如此
So was FDR when he developed the New Deal.
什么时候人的同情心由收入决定了
Since when does one's income determine one's amount of empathy?
你会送你的孩子上公立学校吗
Would you send your kids to public school?
别再提及我们的孩子了
Let's keep our children out of this.
你希望你的孩子赢在起跑线上
You want your kids to have a head start,
胜过那些上公立学校的孩子
to have an advantage over the kids in public schools.
许多收入水平各不相同的美国人
Lots of Americans, of all ranges of income,
都选择送他们的孩子上私立或教区学校
choose to send their children to private or parochial schools.
但你希望你的孩子比其他孩子
But isn't it true that you want your children
更胜一筹  不是吗
to have a leg up on everyone else?
这是平衡差距吗  还是虚伪
Is that balancing the scales? Or is that hypocrisy?
或许  你是根本不想亲自养育他们
Or maybe it's that you didn't want to raise them yourself
才送他们去上寄宿学校
so you sent them to boarding school.
看来你真的很想当总统
You must really want to be president.
我永远都不会
I would never in a million years
在辩论中提到你的孩子
bring up your children in a debate.
你想怎样养育他们是你的私事
The way you choose to raise them is your business.
我想给我的孩子最好的一切吗  当然
Do I want the best for my kids? Yes, I do.
我想你也一样
I imagine you're the same way.
希望是如此
I hope you are.
你们两位肯定都是很棒的母亲
Well, I'm sure you're both excellent mothers.
但也许我们该回到
But perhaps we should get back to
-眼前的问题上  -夏普议员女士
- some of the issues at hand. - Congresswoman Sharp
之前提到性别歧视问题
raised the issue of sexism earlier.
这是很重要的问题  需要进行讨论
Now, it is an important point, and we need to address it.
性别歧视不可取  议员女士说得没错
Sexism is wrong. The Congresswoman is correct
不论何种形式的性别歧视都应被视为违法
in saying that all aspects of it should be illegal.
然后她指责我批评克莱尔·安德伍德
And then, she accused me of being sexist
是性别歧视
for criticizing Claire Underwood.
但这个逻辑放到你身上不也成立吗  夏普女士
But wouldn't that same logic hold true for you, Ms. Sharp?
如果我是男人你还会紧咬我的孩子不放吗
Would you have come after my kids if I were a man?
你不就是想把我抹黑成一个糟糕的母亲
Aren't you trying to paint the picture that I'm a bad mother,
把自己的孩子送去个偏远的地方
shipping my kids off to some far-flung place?
因为你知道如果你能把我抹黑成一个坏母亲
Because you know if you can make me seem like a bad mother,
不可能还会有人支持我
then how could anyone possibly support me?
这不是正面攻击  这只让人恶心
That's not hardball, that is just disgusting.
我必须说我认为邓巴女士说得有道理
Well, I have to say I do think Ms. Dunbar has a point.
说到虚伪
I mean, speaking of hypocrisy,
你不是也送自己的孩子上私立学校吗
don't you send your own kids to private school,
议员女士
Congresswoman?
那不是我的论点  我...
Well, that wasn't my point. I--
你的论点是什么
What was your point?
我
Well, I was, um...
我的论点...
My... My point....
约翰  我想在这个议题上我该说的都说完了
John, I think I've said all I need to say on this subject.
那好吧  议员女士
All right, fair enough, Congresswoman.
下个问题是问你的  邓巴女士
Next question goes to you, Ms. Dunbar.
好了  观众们  第一轮民调结果出来了
Okay, guys, first poll is coming in.
乔治·斯蒂芬诺伯罗斯
ABC新闻首席主播
大多数都支持弗兰克·安德伍德
Most of them give Frank Underwood the win.
爱荷华州
民主党辩论
但优势并不明显
Not by a lot.
但他所做的能打败邓巴  在竞选中领跑吗
But did he do enough to overtake Dunbar, become the front-runner?
乔治  我认为关键并不在于安德伍德做了什么
George, I don't think it's so much what Underwood did,
马修·道得
ABC新闻政治撰稿人
而是他没做什么
but what he didn't do.
他保持了总统的气度
He remained presidential.
当他被攻击时  他保持了风度
And when the attacks came his way, he held the high ground.
邓巴和夏普都出击凌厉
Now, Dunbar and Sharp, they came out swinging,
我认为这对她们都不利
and I think it hurt them both.
没错  但夏普必须有所作为
Yeah, but Sharp had to do something.
她落后其他两人20%
She's 20 points behind the other two.
但性别歧视的论调  还攻击邓巴的孩子
But the sexism thing? And going after Dunbar's kids?
唐娜·布里奇尔
民主党竞选策略顾问
感觉很孤注一掷
It seemed quite desperate.
她确实对邓巴造成了一些伤害
She did do some damage to Dunbar.
这我不敢肯定  邓巴的情况本可能糟
I don't know about that. Dunbar could've fared far worse.
她承受住了打击  也主动出击
She took it on the chin, held her own,
在我看来这是平局
and in my opinion, it was a tie.
但最重要的是这场辩论会带来什么改变吗
But bottom line, does this debate change anything?
这会影响党团会议结果吗
Does it affect the caucus,
这会影响新罕布什尔的初选吗
Does it affect the primary in New Hampshire?
现在离投票还有一个月
We're still over a month out.
这段时间里还有很多变数
And so a lot could change in this process,
但我认为现在的形势对安德伍德有利
but I do think the momentum could shift in Underwood's favor.
让我们别忘记  值得注意的是  现任总统
Let's not forget that it's remarkable that a sitting president
原本并非竞选中的领跑者
isn't considered the front-runner to begin with.
提得很好
That's an excellent point.
从未有过现任总统  要从这么落后的位置往上拼
No incumbent has ever had to fight back from this far...
-喂  -他说她不接电话  先生
- Yes? - He said she's not picking up, sir.
需要我叫他去敲她门吗
Would you like me to have him knock on her door?
不用了  谢谢
No, that's all right. Thank you.
你什么话都没说
You haven't said a word.
你准备辩论几天了
Well, you've been prepping for days.
我觉得你会想静一静
I thought you might want a break from talking.
你对我很失望
You're disappointed in me.
因为孩子被提到了
That the kids got mentioned.
他们还小  没事的
They're teenagers. They'll be fine.
估计还很激动自己被提到了
Probably thrilled... that they got mentioned at all.
要说我对谁失望
If I'm disappointed in anyone,
也是对他把你往火坑里推失望
it's him, for throwing you under the bus.
我今晚跟你一块飞回去
I gotta fly back with you tonight.
你明天不是还有活动吗
Don't you have events tomorrow?
这事更重要
This is more important.
什么事
What is?
献血中心
感谢大家前来
Thank you all for coming in.
请从这边出口出去
If you want to head out this door right here.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
好了  我就不打扰你了
All right, I'll give you some privacy.
大概只需15分钟
This should only take 15 minutes.
-有需要就叫我们  -谢谢你
- So just holler out if you need anything. - Thank you.
拿把椅子来  我们可以边等边聊
Pull up a chair. We can talk while this finishes up.
我也应该献个血
I should be doing this, too.
这里应该够再放把躺椅
I'm sure we could get another lawn chair in here.
我不能献血  以前有毒瘾
I can't. I was a junkie once upon a time.
你管这叫什么颜色  猩红色不贴切
What would you call this color? Scarlet isn't right.
也不是深红或褐红
It's not crimson or maroon.
-洋红色  -洋红色吗
- Carmine. - Carmine?
果然作家就是不一样
You must be a writer.
不  我知道  但她总跟别人说
No, I know that. But you know she always tells everyone
她都是自己烤的  但我知道肯定不是
she bakes them herself and I know she doesn't.
这是本地的
That's local.
谢谢你的支持  等我到了之后见
Thank you for your support. I'll see you when I get there.
为什么我们不能在电话里谈
Is there some reason we couldn't do this by phone?
这需要当面谈清楚
This needed to be in person.
是  但你把你的活动都取消了
Yes, but you canceled all your events.
我想跟你谈谈辩论的事
I want to talk about the debate.
虽然不是我们期望中的大获全胜
You know, it wasn't the home run we hoped for,
但你干得不错  杰姬
but you did great, Jackie.
她一半时间都在防守辩护
She spent half the debate on the defensive.
我让自己难堪了
I humiliated myself.
你只是受了点挫败
You got a little beat up, that's all.
而你下了最重的一拳
And you threw the biggest punch.
你是说你孩子的事吗
Oh, you mean the thing about your kids?
那不是我们说好的
That wasn't what we discussed.
我必须对你下重手  这样她就不能了
I had to hit you hard so she wouldn't.
再说  我们得打消
And besides, we had to dispel any suspicion
我俩串通的猜疑
that you and I might be in concert.
我不喜欢我们现在的这种关系
I'm not comfortable with the dynamic we've established.
什么关系
What dynamic is that?
你拴着我得那条绳索
The leash you have me on.
我得对你言听计从
How I'm supposed to roll over and do any trick you want.
你是不把我当回事
You're taking me for granted.
不然呢  我该怎么着
What, am I supposed to be, uh...
感激你那乏善可陈的热情
appreciative of your lackluster enthusiasm?
你"算是"跟我一队是我天大的幸运吗
How fortunate I am to have you "sort of" on my team?
你不喜欢我们之间的关系
You're not "happy" with our dynamic?
我还不喜欢你的态度
Well, I'm not happy with your attitude.
要说起来  也是你不把我当回事
If anything, you're taking me for granted.
-先生  -我们有约定  杰姬
- Sir-- - We had a deal, Jackie.
我很乐意履行约定
And I am perfectly willing to hold up my end of the bargain.
但别想错了
But do not be under any illusions.
这种合作关系并不平等
This is not a partnership of equals.
完全不平等
Nothing close to it.
你要是想当我的副总统  就得按我说的做
If you are to be my Vice President, you will do what I ask.
我们不能每次
And we will not
因为你对我的要求有所不情愿
have this conversation every time you feel uncomfortable
或不满我的行为
with what I ask you to do,
就要这样争执一番
or how I choose to conduct myself.
这就是我们的关系
That's our dynamic.
我们还要按原时间表来吗
Are we still sticking to the timeline?
对不起  我听不太清
I'm sorry, I couldn't quite hear you.
我们还要按原时间表来吗  我下周退出
Are we still sticking to the timeline? I drop out next week?
没理由不这么做
I see no reason why you shouldn't.
-谢谢您  总统先生  -爱荷华见
- Thank you, Mr. President. - See you in Iowa.
你怎么又把头发染回金色了
Why did you change your hair back to blonde?
这就是你最想问的吗
That's your burning question?
只是好奇
I'm curious.
这对书有什么帮助
How does that help the book?
谁知道呢  但现在我什么灵感都没有
Who knows? But right now, I got nothing.
我们换回金发是因为选民更喜欢金发
We changed it because blonde polls better with the voters.
我们
We?
有一群人
There's a whole gaggle of people
来提议你的造型  穿着
that weigh in on how you look, and what you wear,
考虑活动需要什么
whether an event calls for...
高跟鞋  戴不戴耳环
heels, earrings, no earrings.
你讨厌这样  不是吗
You hate it, don't you?
竞选
Campaigning?
没人喜欢竞选过程
Everybody hates campaigning.
除了政客  他们能从中吸取能量
Except for the politicians. They feed off the energy.
还有从他们配偶那儿
And their spouses.
你觉得弗兰西斯在吸食我吗
You think Francis feeds off me?
你可正在献血呢
You are literally giving your blood.
很多配偶不是政客的人也献血
Plenty of people give blood who aren't married to politicians.
没几个人会帮刚炒了自己的人竞选
Very few people campaign for someone who just fired them.
他告诉你的
He tell you that?
他说他背叛了你
He said he betrayed you.
三天后  你染回金发
Three days later, you change your hair back to blonde
然后辞职  以便"投入竞选"
and resign so you can, quote, "devote yourself to the campaign."
一想就明白了
I did the math.
你和弗兰西斯  你们...
You and Francis, you've....
我们怎么
We've what?
他跟你说了很多
He's shared a lot.
会困扰你吗
Does that bother you?
为什么会
Why would it?
这也是背叛吗
Another betrayal?
不是
No.
你...
You're...
你没事吧
Are you okay?
只是有点头晕
Just a little light-headed.
-给  -谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
我在想
I was thinking.
想什么
About what?
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood?
跳下去
Jumping.
Jumping?
你有过那种感觉吗
You ever have that feeling?
-谈话时  -什么感觉
- Conversation? - Which feeling?
站在桥上  向下看...
On a bridge, you look over and...
往后退
step back.
要帮你叫人吗
Do you need me to get someone?
他求婚时  我说...
He proposed and I said...
我说七年
I said seven years.
七年后如果没问题  就再七年
If it's still good, another seven.
如果不行...
If not...
每七年审视一次
Every seven years.
我不讨厌竞选活动
I don't hate campaigning.
我厌恶的是...
What I hate is...
我有多需要我们
how much I need us.
你们有多需要彼此
How much you need each other?
我没跳下去
I didn't jump.
也没后退
I didn't step back.
我没有...
I didn't...
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood?
-怎么了  -她晕了
- What happened? - She passed out.
我看看  安德伍德夫人
Let me see. Mrs. Underwood?
能听到吗  安德伍德夫人
Can you hear me? Mrs. Underwood?
这三个姑娘  爸爸不是一个人还是怎么
So all these three girls, they got a different papi or what?
一个金发  一个红发  一个黑发
They got the blonde, they got the redhead, they got the brunette.
-这是《裙路口》的剧情吧  -先生
- And that's Petticoat Junction, right? - Sir?
-能私谈吗  -那我走了
- May we speak privately? - Oh, let me let y'all be.
别啊  弗莱迪  你故事正讲到一半
No, Freddie. You're in the middle of your story.
先生  我想跟你私谈
Sir, if you don't mind.
-是机密吗  -不是
- Is it classified? - No, it is not.
那就说
Then talk.
杰姬刚来我办公室  她很沮丧
Jackie just stopped by my office. She's upset.
我觉得我们该更照顾她的想法
I think we need to take her views more into consideration.
她在无理取闹
She's being ridiculous.
我觉得她挺有道理
I think she made some valid points.
你为我还是为她工作
Who do you work for, me or her?
我只是想转达她的担忧
I'm just trying to communicate her concerns.
她最好照说照做  你也是
She'd better get in line and so had you.
如果总要费时间跟下属解释
I'm never gonna win if I have to spend my time
我是赢不了的
explaining myself to my subordinates.
-我还是走吧  -别  弗莱迪  坐下
- Look, let me let you-- - No, no. Now, Freddy, sit down.
记得我们谈过你是怎样对待下属的吗
Do you remember when we talked about how you treat your staff?
你想获胜吗
You want to win?
没有他们  你绝对做不到
You sure as hell won't do it without any of them.
你继续这样  他们都会离开
You keep on like this, you won't have any of them left.
你想谈忠诚吗
Are you talking about loyalty?
我只接受无条件的忠诚
The only brand of that I accept is unconditional.
-做不到就...  -这应该做收费节目
- Anything less is a-- - Y'all should put this on pay-per-view.
你个头挺大  但这家伙
But you. You a big guy. But this sucker,
我见过他吃肋排狼吞虎咽的样子
I've seen him go through a rack of ribs like it was wet tissue.
你赌谁赢
Who'd you put your money on?
我才不会上当
Oh, I'm not gonna fall into that trap.
-当然是你  -先生  您妻子出事了
- You. - Sir? It's your wife.
-她献血晕过去了  -什么
- She passed out giving blood. - What?
没什么大碍  但耶茨先生打过来了
She's okay, but, uh, Mr. Yates is on the line.
我在私人书房接
I'll take it in my private study.
你这么顶撞他毫无益处
Don't do no good callin' a man out like that.
这就像怪蛇有毒牙
It's like... blamin' a snake for having fangs.
我忍不住
I couldn't help myself.
-能帮我个忙吗  -什么
- Could you do me a favor? - What's that?
帮我打掩护  他让我陪但我还有工作
Cover for me. I got work to do and he needs company.
原来在餐馆  我听腻了
Back at the ribs joint, I could just walk back in the kitchen
就回厨房干活儿
when I got tired of hearing him talk.
-好  我就说你上司来了  -谢谢  伙计
- Yeah. I'll tell him your boss came over. - Thank you, brother.
让她接我电话
Put her on the phone with me.
她不让我打电话  但我觉得应该打
She didn't want me to call, but I thought I should.
-她在旁边吗  -她好像是不好意思
- Well, is she nearby? - I think she's embarrassed.
我可是她丈夫
I'm her husband.
护士在照顾她
The nurses are with her.
也许你还是再等等吧
Maybe you should just hold off for a few minutes.
让她的安保队长立刻送她上飞机
Tell the head of her detail to get her on the plane right away.
她得回来看白宫的医生
She has to come back here and see the White House physician.
我猜如果取消活动的话
My guess is she'd be even more embarrassed
她会更不好意思
if she had to cancel her events.
这跟她的感受无关
This isn't about how she feels.
这是为她好
This is about what's best for her.
她不需要看医生  她需要你
She doesn't need a doctor. She needs you.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
她说了些话  说到七年一次
She said some things, about every seven years.
还有站在桥边
About being in limbo, on the edge of a bridge.
听着  就因为我告诉过你
Listen, just because I may have shared with you
一些我们婚姻的事
a few things about our marriage
并不代表你可以指手画脚
does not give you the right to interfere with it.
让她好点了给我打电话
Now, please have her call me when she's ready.
结束了
Well... this is it.
-60天  -60天
- Sixty days. - Sixty days.
那电影吓死我了
That movie freaked me out.
全世界可以在60天内分崩离析
The whole world can fall apart in sixty days.
也可以让人彻底戒酒
Or a guy can get sober.
昨晚睡前我洗了十分钟的手
I washed my hands for ten minutes last night before bed.
你把我从酒鬼改造成了洁癖
You turned me from an alcoholic to a germaphobe.
这交易你不吃亏
That's not a bad trade-off.
过去我自己度过的14年
The 14 years I got by on my own...
跟与你一起度过的这八周比
they mean nothing compared to the last eight weeks
根本一文不值
you've been here with me.
换做是我你也会这么做
You would have done the same for me.
我希望我能做到
I'd like to think so.
你会的
Know so.
我爱你  哥哥
I love you, brother.
到了给我打电话
Call me when you land.
老天  你简直跟萨拉一样
Jesus, you sound like Sarah.
我们要在阔德城
So we want to focus on ad-buys
投放更多广告  在得梅因减少投放量
more in the Quad Cities market, less so in Des Moines.
你在东部的支持率更高
You're stronger in the East
我们得巩固那里的领先地位
and we want to turn our twos there into ones.
辩论之后  "愿景"这个口号
The "vision" message really resonated
在焦点小组中引起很大共鸣
in our focus groups post-debate,
我认为我们应该针对此拍个新广告
so I think we should cut a new ad centered on that
并把它纳入竞选宣传
and weave it into the stump.
先生
Sir?
抱歉  什么
I'm sorry, what?
如果我们把竞选宣传的主题
Are you good if we change the stump
换成"愿景"  您没意见吧
to focus on the "vision" theme?
我想明天一早去新罕布什尔
I want to go to New Hampshire tomorrow, first thing.
您的行程安排是去爱荷华州
We have you going to Iowa.
我知道  但我想更改计划
I know, but I want to change the schedule.
任何人竞选时  都得停下脚步评估形势
In every campaign, there comes a time for taking stock.
夏普竞选团队发表声明
自我反省
A time for soul-searching. And...
在过去的24小时里  我就是那么做的
in the past 24 hours, I have done just that.
而我的决定如下
And the conclusion that I have come to is this:
如果目标是建立一个更安全  兴盛的美国
If the goal is a safer, more prosperous America,
并不非得我参选才能实现
I don't need to run for us to achieve that.
我需要做的  我也鼓励我的支持者做的
All I need to do and what I encourage all of my supporters to do
就是支持希瑟·邓巴成为美国总统
is to help elect Heather Dunbar to the White House.
-叛徒婊子  -虽然我的竞选结束了
- Judas bitch. - While I may be ending my camp--
我就是生气  如果冒犯你了我很抱歉
I'm just pissed off. I'm sorry if I offended.
不知道她给了她什么好处
Yeah, I wonder what she offered her.
什么都没有
Nothing.
得了
Yeah, right.
我确定
I know for a fact.
这事你早就知道吗
You knew about this?
你应该给总统打电话
You should call the President.
"一只浑身是毛  超级可怕的狼蛛  名叫蒂娜
"A very hairy, terribly scary tarantula named Tina.
我是在纽约一个鞋盒里发现她的
I found her in a shoebox in New York City.
我刚发现蒂娜时吓得直叫"
When I first saw Tina I shrieked..."
你害怕吗
Were you scared?
我吓死了
Oh, I was terribly scared.
"蒂娜从左脚的鞋里伸出头来"
"Tina had poked her head up out of the left shoe..."
-我不知道你要来  -她也不知道
- I didn't know you were coming. - She doesn't either.
"所以我呆在那儿  不知道该怎么办
"So there I was, not knowing what to believe.
我该让蒂娜待在鞋盒里还是放她出来"
Should I leave Tina in the shoebox or set Tina free?"
-把她留在鞋盒里  -放她出来
- Leave her in the box! - Set her free!
-放她出来  -把她留在鞋盒里
- Set her free! - Leave her in the box!
我的天  我不知道该怎么办
Oh, my Goodness! I don't know what to do!
什么都不做  不要管她
Nothing! Do nothing!
-我该怎么办  -先生  格雷森先生找您
- What should I do? - Sir, Mr. Grayson needs to speak with you.
-告诉他我会打回去  -他说这事很重要
- Tell him I'll call him back. - He says it's important.
之后再说  我在陪我夫人
Later. I'm with my wife.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do!
你什么都不该做
You shouldn't do anything.
-放她出来  -什么都不做吗
- Let her out! - Don't do anything?
美国总统选举  从两党候选人宣布参选  到党内初选
再到最后普选投票  整个过程往往要持续一年半多
在这漫长的一年半中  最戏剧化的环节  就是候选人电视辩论
在党内初选阶段  参加辩论的人数比较多  电视辩论的次数也比较多
电视辩论一般由两党的全国委员会组织筹划  由各大电视台主持
在2012年的大选中  共和党初选阶段共举行了多达20场的电视辩论
由于在初选辩论中党内候选人彼此攻击过于激烈  导致初选结束后
最后胜出的候选人在普选阶段面对对立党派的对手时
已经伤痕累累  落了下风
所以在即将到来的2016总统大选中
共和党全国委员会决定减少电视辩论次数
初选结束后  两党各自提名一名候选人在普选中出战对垒
普选阶段的电视辩论一般只有四场
三场为总统候选人辩论  一场为副总统候选人辩论
辩论的组织工作由专门的总统选举电视辩论委员会负责
在2012年大选中  三场总统辩论中的第一场最为精彩
一向自诩口才出众的奥巴马  由于过于轻敌
在辩论前没有认真准备  而是跑去参观胡佛水坝
结果在辩论开始后被对手罗姆尼占尽上风
在整场辩论中始终处于绝对劣势
辩论结束后  一直在民调中落后的罗姆尼开始反超奥巴马
可惜后来因飓风等因素  罗姆尼将在辩论中获得的优势又拱手让出